Guide to the Robert Taylor Cole papers, 1933-1991
Duke University. University Archives
Robert Taylor Cole papers 1933-1991
Duke University. University Archives
Cole, Robert Taylor, 1905-1991.
2.5 linear feet Extent: 1500 Items
Robert Taylor Cole was a professor in Duke's Political Science department, specializing in comparative politics, Europe and the British Commonwealth and served as Provost to the University from 1960-1969. The collection includes correspondence, student recommendations, and writings. The material ranges in date from 1933-1991.
UA.05.54.0001
Language: Material in English German
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Robert Taylor Cole papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1964, 1966, and 2013.
Biographical Note
Robert T. Cole was born in Bald Prairie, Texas and educated at the University of Texas (A.B., 1925, A.M., 1927) and Harvard (Ph.D., 1936). He joined the Duke political science faculty in 1935, specializing in comparative politics, Europe and the British Commonwealth. He served the University as its first Provost from 1960 to 1969, and was James B. Duke Professor of Political Science. He retired in 1975, and died in May of 1991. He was awarded the Medal of Freedom in 1945 and the University Medal in 1986.
Collection Overview
Contains correspondence, student recommendations, writings, a photo identification card from Heidelberg University (1933), and a dust jacket from "The Recollections of R. Taylor Cole." At least one letter (in box 1, miscellaneous writings folder) is in German. Also included is a folder which holds a few reports related to Duke University. Box 3 contains two bound volumes of both handwritten and typed letters sent to Cole in 1975, upon his retirement. The material ranges in date from 1933-1991.
Subject Headings
Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University. Dept. of Political Science; Duke University -- History -- 20th century
Related Material
Robert S. Rankin Papers, 1898-1977 (bulk 1927-1976)
Duke University Archives
Robert R. Wilson Papers, 1921-1975
Duke University Archives
John H. Hallowell Papers, 1942-1981
Duke University Archives
Wladyslaw W. Kulski Papers, 1933-1987
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Datebook, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Heidelberg Photo Identification Card, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Writing, Labor Relations in Western Germany, October 1948 (Box 1)
  - Writing, Federalism and Universities in West Germany: Recent Trends, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Writing, Bureaucracy in Transition: Independent Nigeria, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Writing, Three Constitutional Courts: A Comparison, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Writing, The Universities and Governments under Canadian Federalism, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Writing, American Studies in Western Continental European Universities, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous writings (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, A (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Ba-Bk (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Barnes, Samuel H. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Beck, Carl (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Bl-Bz (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Bunn, Ronald F. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Ca-Cl (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Co-Cu (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, D (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Dallmayr, Winfried (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Deener, David R. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, E (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, F-G (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Fletcher, Fred J. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Hi-Hy (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Huntley, James R. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Ha-He (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, I-J (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, K-L (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, LaPalombara, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Ma-Mc (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Me-Mu (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Milburn, Josephine F. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, N-O (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Pa-Pinney (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Piper-Py (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, R (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Sa-Se (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Sh-Sw (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, T-U-V (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Wa-Wh (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Wi-Wz (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, X-Y-Z (Box 2)
  - Student Recommendations, A-Z (Box 2)
  - The Recollections of R. Taylor Cole, Dust Jacket (Box 2)
  - Resolution, University of the South, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Duke University-related reports: Report of the Provost to the President (1966); Report of the Educational Goals Committee about the Commitment to Undergraduate Education (1964); The Library Program of the Duke University Commonwealth Studies Center (1956); and a report on a visit to universities and government officials in Canada (1956). (Box 2)
  - Two bound volumes of handwritten and typed letters sent to Cole in 1975, upon his retirement (Box 3)